how to deploy an AER application
insights resource to store business
Central
Telemetry to get Telemetry data for
business Central you need a place to
store that data and that place is called
application insights it's a it's a
service Insight AER so let's try to
provision one of those I simply in the
aser portal click create resource and I
search for application
insights let's see if we can find that
here application
insights and
um then I create a
resource I need an a subscription I will
pick that and then I need to supply as
always a resource Group I will um just
create I will just uh select one
here then you need to supply the name of
your new instance let me call this
Telemetry uh data and you need to supply
which region this data is stored in this
case we choose North
Europe you can choose between two
different modes of the resource a
classic and a workspace us should should
always use the
workspace uh based one the classic is a
deprecated mode and then you
need um to supply which subscription as
a subscription for the workspace the
workspace is actually where the data is
stored I'll just uh take the defaults I
will click review and
create and wait for Asher to pass that
and then I will click create and this
will initialize the deployment of my new
resource and within a few minutes I will
get my application insights resource and
I'm ready to add that to business
Central it's complete and uh that's it
that's is how you get an application
insights resource for your business
Central
[Music]
telemetry